A few days ago, Anthropic released this
article where they have open sourced
their harness for building longunning
agents. All a harness is is a
coordination layer on top of coding
agents that allows them to work for
hours and hours on a task without
overwhelming their context window. So
basically splitting work between
different agents and context windows on
the same very very large task. And I've
been fascinated with this idea recently.
And so what I want to do with you right
now is take this anthropic harness, put
cloud code into it, and have it work for
24 hours straight and see what results
we get at the end. And I know, I know
this is very experimental. You're not
going to do this kind of thing for a
production application, but I think this
is really exciting to experiment with.
And I really do think that in the near
future, longunning agents are going to
be something we use a lot to kick off
our coding assistants as background
tasks to start an application for us
like build auto proof of concept and
then we come in and keep building on top
of it. And I can tell you that after
reading through this article, which I'll
have linked in the description of
course, and trying it myself already,
the strategies here are legit. And like
I said, I've already been experimenting
with and building these kinds of things,
but I'm definitely going to be taking
inspiration from some of the strategies
that Anthropic has here. And I also
created this really neat Excal diagram
to help you grasp everything that goes
into this harness. And it really is
simple overall, which I appreciate quite
a bit. And there are a lot of really
smart ideas to take out of this. Plus,
of course, you don't have to use cloud
code. This whole harness really is just
a bunch of prompts and files. And so you
could use this with any coding
assistant, codeex, open code, you pick
your poison. So more on this in a bit,
but the application that we're going to
be building over 24 hours is a copy of
claw.ai. So you're probably familiar
with this if you use Claude at all. It
also looks very similar to Claude
desktop. It's just a simple interface
for us to talk to Claude, upload files,
manage projects, and different
conversations. I chose this because
that's the demo they have in the article
that I was showing you earlier. And
whenever I read one of these articles
and they give an example of what they
can build, I always wonder like, is this
actually possible or did they do
something else to make it just look
nicer than it actually turns out? And so
I want to test this article for real by
giving 24 hours for cloud code to build
this thing. And so what you're looking
at right here is what I have from a
previous execution only after a couple
of hours. There are a lot of features
missing here if I were to poke around.
And so we're going to see after 24
hours, can we build this but completely
working with conversations and artifacts
and files and projects, all the features
that we have with Claude as the
application. Now I could go right into
the live demo and we'll do that in a
little bit, but the real value for you
is understanding how this harness works
even so you can take ideas from this to
evolve your own system for AI coding. So
I'll explain this really quick because
it is pretty simple. Overall, it relies
on the concept of testdriven
development, which is very powerful for
AI coding. We define the success
criteria, all of our tests upfront
before we do any of the actual coding.
And so then we're constantly checking
our work against this set of tests that
defines what it means to have a finished
product. It's very cool. And all the
ideas that I have in this diagram are
coming directly from this article and
then also the open source repo for the
harness, which I'll link to below. You
can start using this right away and this
is what we're going to be using for our
live demo in a bit. So with this
harness, everything starts with the app
spec text file. I typically call this a
PRD. It's basically the scope of work
for what you want to build for your MVP.
So this is the primary context that goes
into the first session that our harness
kicks off. And this is the session for
our initializer agent. The sole job of
our initializer agent is to get our
project set up. So when it finishes,
we're not going to have anything
actually working yet, but we're going to
have these four things created to then
go into our coding agents. And we'll get
into this in a little bit. And so the
first thing that our initializer agent
creates is this feature list JSON file.
This has the 200 or more test cases that
need to pass for our application to be
considered complete. And this number is
configurable in the anthropic harness. I
know that is an insane number, but like
I said, this is very experimental. We
just want to see what it looks like to
have a coding agent run for a very long
time implementing a lot of different
things. And so all of this is just based
on our PRD breaking it down into very
granular tasks. And then we also create
a script to initialize our project like
get the website spun up. We create the
scaffolding. So kind of like the
boilerplate having that in place for our
coding agents. And then finally we
initialize a git repository because git
is absolutely crucial for any AI coding
system. So with the initializer agent,
we've covered two out of the three core
artifacts for our harness. We have the
feature list and the initialization
script. The last core artifact here is
our claude progress. This is the file
that is updated at the end of every
session, giving a summary of what was
just done. This is how our initializer
agent and then each of our coding agents
are able to communicate with each other
even though we create a brand new
context window between each agent. And
so the way that the initializer agent
works is it sets up all the scaffolding
and then it gives an overview of what
it's set up in this file. Then we go to
the second session in the system which
is the first time we're running a coding
agent. And so it is going to go to the
cloud progress understand what was just
done by the initializer. Then it's going
to spin up the website with the init
script. And then it'll read the feature
list to figure out what is the first
feature that I should knock out. And
then it's going to run through this
process to kind of catch itself up to
speed on what we have in the codebase,
implement the next feature, document
that commit, and then go on to the next
loop of the coding agent. So it gets its
bearings. I often call this priming.
It's going to understand what we already
have, including reading the feature list
to figure out what to build next. It's
going to maybe do some regression
testing, making sure that previous
features are still working. That's a
really important part of this harness as
well. It'll pick the next feature,
implement and test it, and then it'll
update the cloud progress with a summary
of what it did, and then make a get
commit. So, we have a save state after
each one of our context windows, and
then it's going to loop n number of
times. This is going to go over and over
and over again until all of the test
cases are passing in our feature list
JSON file. And what allows this to go
forever basically is just the fact that
we have this new context window every
time we go into the next coding agent.
And we have these core artifacts plus
the process to make it so that even
though we start a new context window
every time, we can quickly catch
ourselves up to speed on what has to be
implemented. Even do a bit of regression
testing before we now go into the next
feature. So each coding agent is very
granular and focused and that's what
makes this process pretty reliable
overall. And there are also some
guardrails that we have in place for
security. There are some validation
tools so the agent can actually visit
the browser and verify things visually.
It's a pretty cool process. So we'll get
into that as we start the demo here. Now
if you thought that we're using the
Claude Code CLI for this harness, you my
friend are mistaken. We have true power
and flexibility when we interact with
cloud code directly in our Python or
TypeScript code. And so for this
demonstration, this harness that we're
going to be using in a little bit here,
we are using the Claude agent SDK to
create our Claude code client and
interact with it directly in Python
code. And I really do think that this is
also the direction that we're heading
with coding assistance because it's
really easy to build our own systems
like this harness when we control things
programmatically. And there are a lot of
other AI coding assistants like Codeex
and Open Code that are also coming out
with SDKs. And I even included the
Codeex SDK along with the clawed agent
SDK in the remote agentic coding system
that I covered in the live stream on
Saturday, which is very exciting by the
way. But I've done a lot of
experimentation with this. So that's why
I'm saying that I could very easily take
this repository, swap out cloud code for
codecs, and then still use the exact
same harness because it is just those
artifact files. and then the prompts
that I'll show you later as well. So
with that, let's actually get into the
repository here and spin up our demo.
All right, so I have the repository
cloned locally and going through the
prerequisites here to get everything
ready to run is really, really
straightforward. The only thing that I
tweaked in my local version is I
absolutely do not want to use my
enthropic API key. That is going to
charge me out the wazoo with the task
running this long. I definitely want to
take advantage of my Mac subscription
and use my Claude subscription token.
And so the way that you get that is you
do claude and then setup dash token.
It'll walk you through a little ooth
flow. It'll give you a token that you
can set as the environment variable cla
token. So you just have to set that
instead of your enthropic API key. And
then I changed the code right here. And
then I also removed something at the top
of the client function. So that's all
you have to do if you want to replicate
what I set up here. Otherwise, you can
of course use your anthropic API key.
Just get ready to pay a good amount,
especially if you're using open opus 4.5
for your coding agent. Other than that
though, I just followed all the steps in
the readme here. And so it got to the
point where now I can run this command
right here. So I run the autonomous
agent demo and then all I have to select
is the directory that I want to build
this project in. And so I'm just using
the exact same app spec that came with
this repository because like I said, I
want to clone Claude just like they have
in the article. So they already had this
full prompt created for me, which is
very, very detailed. Obviously, we need
something very detailed in order to
create that featureless JSON file that
has all of these different features and
test cases that we need passing for the
app to be complete. So this is my app
spec. I'm going to send this in as
context for the application build. And
then once I kick things off, that's when
I want to kind of explore the prompts
more with you and also talk about how we
are invoking the claude agent SDK. But
right now, let's go ahead and spin this
off. And this begins the 24 hours for
our demo here. So, autonomous coding
agent demo. We're using Opus 4.5 for our
model. And we are going to start with
our initializer agent. So, this is
session number one. just like I was
showing in the Excal Draw diagram and we
are using this appspec as our PRD that
outlines all of the features that we
want to build. And so all the tool calls
that we typically see within the Cloud
Code CLI, we can see these here. It
doesn't look quite as pretty, but we can
watch it work. And so this is it's going
to go for a while. The first session
does take 10 to 20 minutes because it
has to generate those 200 very detailed
test cases. So, we have to be patient
and that's why I'm going to take this as
an opportunity to show you around the
prompts more and then we'll come back to
this when we get to the first coding
agent session. So, the big question you
have right now is where do the prompts
come from? Because we're not using the
cloud code CLI. We're not entering
anything in ourselves or using any kind
of slash command. But that my friend is
the beauty of the claude agent SDK
because within our Python code we are
loading the initializer prompt from
right here and then every session after
that is just going to be loading in this
coding prompt. So they're just markdown
documents just like our rules and
commands that you're typically working
with with your AI coding assistants. And
so for our initializer here, everything
that we're about to go through should
ring a lot of bells because we're just
working with the same process that we
outlined in the Excaladraw. And so we're
giving it context like you were the
first agent in a longunning autonomous
development process. And so you start by
reading the appspec or the PRD. This
contains the complete specification for
what you need to build. And then based
on that PRD, you're going to create that
massive feature list JSON file that I
showed you briefly earlier. So it's very
very structured for every single feature
that we need to build. We have the
category, the description, the steps to
validate the feature. This is really
cool. And then also just true or false.
Is this currently passing? So whenever a
coding agent knocks out one of these
features, it just goes back in the
feature list JSON and changes this from
false to true. So if I like scroll down
to the very bottom here, this is from an
old run, by the way, it would just like
change this from false to true. And then
we create that initialization script so
the coding agent can spin up the website
every time we have a new context window.
It initializes the git repository and
then creates the boilerplate for our
application structure. And so then the
coding agents already have at least
something to work on top of even though
nothing's actually working in the app at
this point. And then finally, it creates
that claude progress to just give a
summary of what it set up. And so this
is an example of the cloud progress
right here. This is completely wiped and
uh redone every time we have the end of
a session. So that is the initializer.
And if we go look at our terminal right
here, it is still running. So at this
point, we've created our feature set.
Now we're just working on some of these
other things like creating the initial
project directory structure. So, it's
working through everything that we just
saw in the initializer prompt. Now, once
the coding agents start running, that's
when we use our coding prompt. And so,
this one is a little bit more
complicated, but it's still not too bad
overall. And so, we obviously have to
start by getting our bearings because
we're dropping a fresh context window
into an existing project. And so there's
a couple of commands that we want to run
just like understand our PRD. Look at
the feature list to see what we should
build next. Look at the cloud progress
so we can see what the initializer agent
did if this is our second session.
Otherwise, we're looking at what the
coding agent did in the previous run.
Taking advantage of the git history as
well. Like I said, git is a very crucial
part of our process and our harness
here. And then we're going to start up
the servers with the initialization
script. So going back to our diagram
here, we are reading all of our core
artifacts and taking advantage of those
in our agent loop here. And then we're
going to do some verification. So before
we do anything new, it's going to do a
little bit of regression testing. So
just spot checking here. We look at a
couple of the more recently implemented
features that are marked as true uh for
the passing in the featureless JSON
here. And it's just going to make sure
that those things are still working. And
this is really important because as
we're building out so much code in our
project here, we might be breaking old
things. So I really appreciate that
regression testing is built into this.
Now, if there are any issues that are
found, then we're going to address them.
So go back to the feature JSON, mark it
as false, fix the issue, and then go
through the steps again to verify that
everything is working. And we have the
Puppeteer MCP server attached to the
coding assistant. Like if we go and look
at how everything is configured here.
We're giving it the Puppeteer MCP
server. So it can actually go and verify
that things are working on the website.
Like this is what we have right now for
our initializer agent running. It
actually spun up the website to make
sure that our little hello world
boilerplate is working. And so as it's
building out the application, it can
even validate things visually, which is
very, very powerful. So we'll see a lot
more of this as it's building things
out. And then to finish off the coding
prompt here, obviously once it does all
of its regression testing, it's going to
choose one feature from our JSON file.
So kind of like you know the next one
that has passes as false. And then it's
going to implement it, test it, go back
and mark it as complete after it does
even like the full browser automation
validation with Puppeteer like we just
saw. And we have clear instructions
here. Make sure that you only updated
the passes field. you cannot change
anything else because one thing that
coding assistants do a lot is they get
lazy and they say like oh I did the
first four steps of validation I don't
need to do the last one so let me just
remove it so we're making sure we avoid
that by saying you cannot update the
steps you can only update false to true
and then of course our very last step is
to make that save state with git so we
are committing our progress and then
updating the clawed progress so that the
next coding agent can read through
exactly what was done with the last loop
and So then we end our session and the
rest of this here is just kind of
miscellaneous instructions. That's
really the end of the process that we
have for the coding agent and we're just
going to be running this over and over
and over again. So at this point we've
gone through all the prompting for this
system. It really is simple. We rely on
these core artifacts. We have one prompt
for the initializer and then one prompt
for all of our coding agents. And by the
way, if you want to understand best
practices for security, permissions,
things like that, for defining our
agents in code, this repository is
fantastic for this. I don't want to dive
into the code too much, but it's worth
showing you a little bit how this works
with the cloud agent SDK. So, when we
create our client, first of all, we pass
in a project directory. The coding agent
is only able to operate in this project
directory, which is already a good layer
of security, right? The file operations
are restricted to the project directory
only. We have our sandbox environment.
And then we have our permissions where
we just accept all edits. So we don't
need human approval for changes.
Obviously that would not work for an
autonomous system. And then we define
the specific commands that claude code
is able to run in the cloud agent SDK.
Reading files, writing files, using the
Puppeteer MCP server for the browser
automation, all that good stuff. And it
even goes so far as having a hook. So
every time we use a tool, if it is
running a bash command, we also have
this entirely separate Python script
that manages the different kinds of bash
commands that we're allowing cloud code
to run. So it can't do things like
delete directories or work outside of
our current codebase. And so this is
really really powerful. It gets quite
technical, but if you are more technical
and you want to understand like how can
it end processes without killing itself,
for example, it's definitely worth
diving into this. And then finishing
things off for the client here, we have
the MCP server for Puppeteer, which by
the way, the Puppeteer MCP server, it
takes a while to validate things cuz the
agent, it spins up the browser, it waits
for things to load, then it clicks on a
button and waits for that to load. And
so we go for 24 hours, but it's not like
we're spending millions and millions of
tokens because we are waiting quite a
while for all the browser automation
stuff. But yeah, we have our system
prompt that we can customize as well,
which is really cool. We define our
model, all the allowed tools and the
hooks and things, our current working
directory. There's so much configuration
that we have for the cloud agent SDK,
which is part of why we need something
like this when we have this harness that
we want to control so much. And so when
we actually invoke the agent, if it is
the first run, we're going to get the
initializer prompt. Otherwise, we get
the coding prompt. It's just reading
these in from these markdown documents.
And then we send that into this function
right here, which leverages the client
that I showed you just now, how we
define. So it runs this query here with
the latest message, which this is going
to be the message that's just loaded in
from one of these markdown documents. We
stream out all of the text and tool
calls and we put that out to the
terminal. That's exactly what we're
looking at right here as we have our
autonomous agent running. All right, our
initializer agent has finished and we
have the first commit for our initial
setup. And one thing that this harness
that this application does after every
session is it automatically runs all the
tests to give us a progress update. Now
obviously right here we have a progress
report of 0% because the initializer
agent is only creating the foundation.
it is not responsible for doing any
feature development that would make one
of these tests pass. And so that brings
us to the second session or the first
time we run our coding agent. It is
going to create that secured sandbox
environment and then go through the
exact process that we saw in the coding
agent prompt. So it does its prime here
where it lists out the files, looks at
the PRD and the cloud progress from the
initializer agent, looks at the git log
and the feature list, all these things
that we've already gone over. It spins
up the website with that initialization
script and then we can see it using the
Puppeteer MCP server to visualize
things, even take a screenshot. It's
looking at the API. You just saw it go
there like just very briefly. It was
doing a little bit of work and we can
also see the website more plainly if we
just like visit it in our own browser as
well. So this is my personal browser and
then what we're looking at right here,
there's nothing being shown right now,
but this is the browser that the agent
is currently operating in. So this is
the what we have built so far as I have
the first coding agent run. So it's kind
of just creating the initial user
interface at this point. I'm not going
to click through things right now, but
most of this stuff is probably not
working at all because we have just
gotten started with the process here.
And the first agent is going to be very
granular in what it builds. So all this
output here, I know that it's a little
ugly, but it's pretty much what we see
in the Cloud Code CLI. And so it just
goes through the first feature and does
all the testing it needs. And then in a
little bit here, it'll probably update
the cloud progress and then move on to
our second coding agent session. And so
at this point, I've covered everything
that I want to cover. And so what I'm
going to do here is pause and then next
time you see me, the 24 hours is going
to be up. We're going to come back to
the terminal here, see what session
we're on, see how many tests are
passing, and then we'll also see what
our application looks like. So, I'm
doing this live with you. I have no idea
how it it's going to turn out. I've
tested the same thing, but only with a
few hours. That's all I gave it. And so,
yeah, let's come back together and see
how it shapes up. All right, we are now
at the 24-hour mark, and we have gotten
to the 54th coding agent session.
Absolutely crazy. I have no idea how
many tokens I've used for this, but it
is probably a lot. Thank goodness I'm
using my Claude subscription. And we
have 54% of our tests passing at this
point, which after an entire day might
not seem like a very high percentage,
but we have given it a lot of different
features to work through and implement.
So having over 100 of the tests passing
at this point is pretty cool. And going
to our browser here, this is the website
that I have spun up in my own browser,
not the testing one with Puppeteer. It
is pretty impressive everything that we
have built out right now. And honestly,
I don't even know what the last half of
the tests are for because it already
feels like I have a completely
functional clone of claw.ai. And it's
cool. We can go through all of the past
conversations that it generated as it
was verifying things through each of the
loops. We have really nice markdown
formatting. We are able to create these
different HTML pages and even write and
execute code. We have a settings where
we can change the theme and our default
model and a slider for the max tokens.
Like this is just so so featurerich.
Like it's a lot more than if you were to
just in a single prompt ask it to make a
clone cuz it's not going to build out
all this functionality. Even being able
to see the token count for the responses
and I'll create a new chat here and send
in something myself. So I can see the
number of characters and estimated
tokens for my own prompts. And you can
see here that like the UI isn't perfect.
And so I definitely didn't expect this
to be perfect. We still want to come in
and add a human in the loop. But it
still is really cool how much I was able
to build here without laying a finger on
anything. And honestly, who knows? If I
let it go for another day and it goes
through all of the features, maybe this
would be an absolutely perfect
application cuz it really is crazy the
kinds of things we can build with Claude
Opus 4.5. And then having a harness like
this to let it do so much validation and
iteration on an application. And also
it's really cool to look through the
featureless JSON as well. So passes is
true for a ton of these different
features now. So I have to scroll all
the way down to the middle to start
seeing the ones that are false for
passes. So now we start to see the next
things that we have to work on. And
these are very very specific scroll bars
and mobile styling and dividers. like
we're getting to the very nitty-gritty
details of making a very complete Claude
clone. And then in the cloud progress,
we can see what happened in the previous
session and then even an overview of
what happened in sessions before that.
One thing that's really confusing here
is I don't know why it says session 34
when we know that we're on session 54.
So like the harness seems to have veered
off a little bit, but it still is
knocking out feature after feature
pretty quickly. I've been watching the
logs towards the end of the execution
and that's one of the things that I was
really nervous with is that like it'd
work really well for the first, you
know, 10 20 sessions, but then it would
start to hallucinate a lot and like go
through features willy-nilly here and
start to totally mess up the cloud
progress, but like overall it seems to
be very aligned even as we go through
dozens of sessions. So, I got to hand it
to Anthropic here. Overall, I'm very
impressed. Not that I haven't had these
kind of longunning sessions work before,
but being able to do something really
out of the box with a resource that they
have open sourced is really fantastic.
And so I would encourage you to try this
out yourself. Clone this repository that
again I will have linked in the
description. You can even go within the
app spec here and change what you want
to build. So if you don't just want to
follow along with what they show here
and build the claude clone, you can
build any application that you want, any
kind of backend, any kind of front end,
it works with all of this. you just
probably want to have some kind of user
interface to take advantage of the
Puppeteer MCP server integration. But
otherwise, it's really up to you what
you want to use this harness to create.
And so, I hope that you appreciated this
video and it gave you some ideas for
ways that you can build this kind of
harness into your own AI coding system.
So, if you appreciated this video and
you're curious how you can take these
kinds of ideas and use them to build
your own system for AI coding,
definitely check out the Dynamus Agentic
Coding course that I'll have a link to
in the description and the pin comment.
This is the best resource you'll find on
the internet for learning how to build
reliable and repeatable workflows for AI
coding. So, definitely check it out and
I will see you in the next video.